# **SERGEY RADKOV**

Boise ID USA | (208) 283-9080 | radkovsn@gmail.com | www.sradkov.com

www.linkedin.com/in/radkovsn https://qithub.com/eriixon

Permanent Work Authorization No Visa Sponsorship Required Open to Relocation

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

## **Proficiencies**

HTML / CSS Node.js
JavaScript NPM
Bootstrap Bower
Angular.js GitHub
jQuery Heroku

API's Visual Studio Code

Facebook Messenger

# Have experience with

Foundation MVC Pattern

Twilio Java Firebase C#

JSData IntelliJ IDEA MySQL Vue.JS

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Messenger Bot for Better Business Bureau

Facebook Messenger Bot is the back-end application for Better Business Bureau to find appropriate businesses through Facebook Messenger. In this project are used Node JS as back-end, BBB API (to look for find trustworthy businesses in North America), Google Maps API(to identify user location), the huge dictionary of US states/cities and Facebook Messenger Platform.

https://m.me/BBBSnakeRiverRegion

# **Quickbooks Helper Web Application**

Self-Service customer updater tool. Allows a customer to enter their phone information and verify that they are a customer, and then allows the customer edit their name, address, and email information. This information is then updated into QuickBooks(tm) using the QuickBooks(tm) SDK.

https://gbemailgrabber.herokuapp.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Junior Web Developer with a passion for online businesses has extensive knowledge of business analysis and substantial experience creating logical and innovative solutions to complex problems to increase efficiency, with 5+ years' telematics service promotion and 8 years' management experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Web Development Immersive Full Stack Course**

BoiseCodeWorks | Boise, Idaho | 2016 The leading premier coding bootcamp in Idaho.

# Master's Degree | Transport Management

(combined bachelor/master program)

State University of Management | Moscow, Russia | 1997 – 2002 Russia's leading university in the field of management education.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Web Developer**

Saharacase LLC | Boise, Idaho | 11.2016 - now

Co-developed a vibrant, secure website using interactive features and SEO best practices to optimize traffic, page views and the user experience (UX), developed product web templates for the main marketplaces (Amazon, eBay, Walmart, etc).

### **Web Developer**

freelance | Boise, Idaho | 06.2016 - now

Created and maintained web pages using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AngularJS and Node.js, optimized web pages for mobile, and debugged for better code, updated existing code and learned new technologies on the fly.

# **Senior Product Engineer**

Volvo Truck Russia | Moscow, Russia | 2010 -2015 A branch of Volvo Trucks, a global truck manufacturer.

Promoted Volvo telematics services, provided technical support for 600+ customers and 100+ team members, established new consulting service using Volvo's telematics.

## **Transportation Coordinator**

TOTAL E&P Russia | Moscow, Russia | 2008 - 2010 Subsidiary of TOTAL S.A., a multinational oil and gas company.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Practical problem solver with exceptional attention to detail
- Strong presentation, communication and negotiation skills
- Demonstrated success in project and staff management
- Ability to adapt to rapidly changing environments
- International experience and bi-lingual in English and Russian